<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Forest for the Tree</title><link href="http://rcushen.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://rcushen.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://rcushen.github.io/</id><updated>2010-12-06T10:20:00+11:00</updated><entry><title>Jupyter Notebooks</title><link href="http://rcushen.github.io/jupyter-notebooks.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-06T10:20:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-06T10:20:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Cushen</name></author><id>tag:rcushen.github.io,2010-12-06:/jupyter-notebooks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An exposition of Jupyter Notebooks in Pelican&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This will be the first post in our new Pelican blog! You can add any code or markdown cells to this Jupyter notebook, and they will be rendered on your blog. On the other hand, we denounce with righteous indignation and dislike men who are so beguiled and demoralized by the charms of pleasure of the moment, so blinded by desire, that they cannot foresee the pain and trouble that are bound to ensue; and equal blame belongs to those who fail in their duty through weakness of will, which is the same as saying through shrinking from toil and pain. These cases are perfectly simple and easy to distinguish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some Sample Cells&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a free hour, when our power of choice is untrammelled and when nothing prevents our being able to do what we like best, every pleasure is to be welcomed and every pain avoided. But in certain circumstances and owing to the claims of duty or the obligations of business it will frequently occur that pleasures have to be repudiated and annoyances accepted. The wise man therefore always holds in these matters to this principle of selection: he rejects pleasures to secure other greater pleasures, or else he endures pains to avoid worse pains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;random&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;randint&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;34
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;matplotlib.pyplot&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kn"&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;plt&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;matplotlib&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;inline&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="n"&gt;plt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;])&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;plt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;show&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="png" src="http://rcushen.github.io/images/output_2_0.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Even More Maths&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, we denounce with righteous indignation and dislike men who are so beguiled and demoralized by the charms of pleasure of the moment, so blinded by desire, that they cannot foresee the pain and trouble that are bound to ensue; and equal blame belongs to those who fail in their duty through weakness of will, which is the same as saying through shrinking from toil and pain. These cases are perfectly simple and easy to distinguish. In a free &lt;strong&gt;hour&lt;/strong&gt;, when our power of choice is untrammelled and when nothing prevents our being able to do what we like best, every pleasure is to be welcomed and every pain avoided. But in certain circumstances and owing to the claims of duty or the obligations of business it will frequently occur that pleasures have to be repudiated and annoyances accepted. The wise man therefore always holds in these matters to this principle of selection: he rejects pleasures to secure other greater pleasures, or else he endures pains to avoid worse pains.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="python"></category><category term="data"></category></entry><entry><title>Some Thoughts on Cheese</title><link href="http://rcushen.github.io/some-thoughts-on-cheese.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-04T10:20:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-04T10:20:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Cushen</name></author><id>tag:rcushen.github.io,2010-12-04:/some-thoughts-on-cheese.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short piece on my feelings regarding cheese&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cheese is not the worst. But I must explain to you how all this mistaken idea of denouncing pleasure and praising pain was born and I will give you a complete account of the system, and expound the actual teachings of the great explorer of the truth, the master-builder of human happiness. No one rejects, dislikes, or avoids pleasure itself, because it is pleasure, but because those who do not know how to pursue pleasure rationally encounter consequences that are extremely painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Made from Milk?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor again is there anyone who loves or pursues or desires to obtain pain of itself, because it is pain, but because occasionally circumstances occur in which toil and pain can procure him some great pleasure. To take a trivial example, which of us ever undertakes laborious physical exercise, except to obtain some advantage from it? But who has any right to find fault with a man who chooses to enjoy a pleasure that has no annoying consequences, or one who avoids a pain that produces no resultant pleasure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some Controversial Views&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons for and against. For:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's delicious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protein-rich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What else?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are also some things that score against it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This thing here, that I can't quite recall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet another problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where were we up to?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also can write some code to show this, conclusively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="n"&gt;cheese&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;good&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To take a trivial example, which of us ever undertakes laborious physical exercise, except to obtain some advantage from it? But who has any right to find fault with a man who chooses to enjoy a pleasure that has no annoying consequences, or one who avoids a pain that produces no resultant pleasure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all of us in the gutter, but some are looking up to the stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn't Oscar Wilde the best!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, no one rejects, dislikes, or avoids pleasure itself, because it is pleasure, but because those who do not know how to pursue pleasure rationally encounter consequences that are extremely painful.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="reviews"></category></entry><entry><title>My First Review</title><link href="http://rcushen.github.io/my-first-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-12-03T10:20:00+11:00</published><updated>2010-12-03T10:20:00+11:00</updated><author><name>Ryan Cushen</name></author><id>tag:rcushen.github.io,2010-12-03:/my-first-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Check out my latest keyboard!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Keyboard Review&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following is a review of my favourite mechanical keyboard. But I must explain to you how all this mistaken idea of denouncing pleasure and praising pain was born and I will give you a complete account of the system, and expound the actual teachings of the great explorer of the truth, the master-builder of human happiness. No one rejects, dislikes, or avoids pleasure itself, because it is pleasure, but because those who do not know how to pursue pleasure rationally encounter consequences that are extremely painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Subtitle or Two&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nor again is there anyone who loves or pursues or desires to obtain pain of itself, because it is pain, but because occasionally circumstances occur in which toil and pain can procure him some great pleasure. To take a trivial example, which of us ever undertakes laborious physical exercise, except to obtain some advantage from it? But who has any right to find fault with a man who chooses to enjoy a pleasure that has no annoying consequences, or one who avoids a pain that produces no resultant pleasure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;WORKING TITLE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SECTION 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what this section is about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why it matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;research or examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;takeaways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SECTION 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what this section is about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why it matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;research or examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;takeaways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;SECTION 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what this section is about&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why it matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;research or examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;takeaways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;</content><category term="reviews"></category><category term="data"></category></entry></feed>